JOSHUA OLANREWAJU ABEFE

Web Developer

Address: 14 Victoria Street, Yaba, Lagos.

E-Mail: Joshabefedev@gmail.com · **Tel**: 09081539986 | 08072099452

<u>LinkedIn Profile</u> · <u>Portfolio</u> · <u>GitHub</u>

Objectives

Meticulous web Developer with entry-level experience specializing in web development, user interface design, and passion for modern and responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. Adept at identifying opportunities to enhance front-end design and improve the user experience.

Education

❖ Faedat College of technology, Lagos.

Diploma - Computer Science

Completion: 2013

Relevant Coursework: Computer Fundamentals, Typography, eColor Theory, Vectors, Illustration.

* The Polytechnic, Ibadan, Oyo.

OND - Business Administration

2017-2019

❖ Inspire Vocational Academies, Lagos.

Diploma - Web Design & Development Concentration

Completion: 2021

Relevant Coursework: Website Design, User Experience, Client-Side Development, Web Page Programming, Database Management Systems, Object-Oriented Programming, Web Architecture, Mobile Application Development.

Experience

Inspire Software Academies
Internship

Feb 2021 – July 2021

- Coordinate with the web development team to design user interfaces for client websites using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript. Which included developing pages, coding, and debugging.
- Served as the point of contact for client stakeholders throughout all phases of the development lifecycle, fielded quality concerns, identified solutions, and aligned deliverables with customer business specifications
- Collaborated with back-end developers to develop an ecommerce website to sell products online. Increased company sales by 58%.
- Partnered with cross-functional teams to refine the user experience and led all front-end development efforts to ensure alignment with quality standards.
- On-boarded and mentored 5 new front-end developers through regular coaching sessions and work reviews. Improved KPI attainment 22%.
- Created a website and Facebook-linked donations website for a local charity. Raised donations by 38%. Over 160 communities reached with 200,000 beneficiaries.

Chevron Nigeria Limited, Lekki, Lagos.

Supply Chain Management Intern

Feb 2020 – Jan 2021

- Focused on projects to improve the operations of the strategic procurement & contract department and other closely connected departments.
- Conducted professional market research, communicated with clients, and resolved any client problematic issues.
- Performed multiple daily procurement functions, completed weekly reports, and executed other tasks as required by managers.

Key Skills

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, PHP, MySQL
- CSS Pre-processors Sass, LESS
- Responsive Web Design
- Version Control Git
- CSS and JS Frameworks Bootstrap, jQuery, React.js
- Content Management Systems (CMS) WordPress
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Performance Testing
- Cross-Browser Compatibility
- Load Testing & Debugging
- Leadership Skills
- Ability to work with minimum supervision
- Ability to create new ideas
- Collaborating with product and development teams
- Strong verbal and written communication skills
- Teamwork Skills
- Critical Thinking
- Profound creative
- Analytical problem-solving and Troubleshooting skills

Certifications

- Front End Web Developer Professional Certification by W3C
- The Web Developer Bootcamp (Udemy)
- Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools: Bootstrap 4
- Pluralsight Front End Web Development Certification

Hobbies

- Listening to Music
- Exercising
- Playing Video Gam